少数派报告
不戴眼镜我简直跟瞎子一样
You know how blind I am without them.
霍华，不要哭
Howard, don't cry.
凶杀案
Murder.
（被害人） （莎拉马克斯、唐诺杜宝）
（犯罪预防中心）
（华盛顿特区）
-祝你好运，约翰 -开始阵痛了吗？
Good luck, John.  Any contractions?
只有你让我头痛
Only the ones you give me.
（2054年）
（行凶者） （霍华马克斯）
-最新状况？ -红球，双尸命案
What's coming?  Red Ball, double homicide.
一男一女 凶手：男性，白种人，40余岁
One male, one female. Killer's male, white, 40s.
亚嘉莎将时间锁定在早上8：04 双胞胎对时间还不是很确定
Agatha nailed the time at 8:04 a.m. The twins are a little fuzzy on that.
地点未知，远程目击已联机
Location's still uncertain. Remote witnesses are plugged in.
案号：1108
This will be case number 1108.
早安，警官们
Morning, detectives.
1108案已被预视先知发现 录制于影像系统中
Case number 1108, previsualized by the PreCogs...
递减排列于犯罪预防目录
...recorded on holosphere by Precrime's Qstacks.
共同见证人有凯瑟琳詹姆士 和法兰克波勒审判长
My fellow witnesses are Dr. Katherine James and Chief Justice Frank Pollard.
早安
Good morning.
见证人愿授权侦办案吗？
Will the witness preview and validate 1108 at this time?
同意，我授权
Affirmative. I will validate.
逮捕他
Go get them.
-请待命 -凶案时间上午8：04
Standby.  Time of murder: 8:04 a.m.
离现在24分13秒 这是红球状况
That is 24 minutes, 13 seconds from now. This is a Red Ball.
不戴眼镜我简直跟瞎子一样
You know how blind I am without them.
霍华马克斯，你在哪里？
All right, Howard Marks, where are you?
霍华？霍华，吃早餐！
Howard? Howard, breakfast.
七年又八十天以前
Four score and seven years ago...
-他看起来好面熟 -谁？
He looked familiar.  Who?
站在对街公园里那个人
A man standing in the park across the street.
-我以前见过他 -确定？
Seen him before.  How can you tell?
没眼镜你不是像瞎子？ 你的眼镜呢？
You're blind without your glasses. Where are your glasses?
-在卧室 -你快迟到了
In the bedroom.  You're running out of time.
不戴眼镜我简直跟瞎子一样
You know how blind I am...
本区有八位霍华马克斯 正在筛选
I show eight Howard Markses in the District. Sorting by race and age.
查驾照和注册纪录 我想办法确定一个地址
Run their license and registration. See if I can capture an address here.
我今天可能去打曲棍球
I was thinking I'd stay home today.
-你不是要开会吗？ -我太卖力工作了
What about your meeting?  I've been working too much.
-这影像可以抓下来吗？ -不清晰
Can you grab that?  It's unclear.
-查到六份驾照 -请拿过来
Six licenses. Where do you want them?  Over here, please.
不戴眼镜我简直跟瞎子一样
You know how blind I am without them.
抓到了 甘斯柏街，4421号
Got him in the Foxhall. 4421 Gainsborough.
叫特区警局出动 说我们已经在途中
Send DCPD. Set up a perimeter. Tell them we're en route.
我想打曲棍球，今天不想出门
I was thinking maybe I'd play hooky, stay home today.
-“贡献一己心力的时候到了” -你觉得怎么样？
"We've come to dedicate a portion..."  What do you think?
-你不是要开会吗？ -改时间
What about your meeting?  I'll reschedule.
我太卖力工作了
I've been working too much anyway.
-“这么做…”，好啊 -我们一起吃午饭
"But in a larger s..." Good.  We could have lunch together.
-你觉得呢？ -“我们无法奉献”
What do you say?  "We cannot consecrate...
-好啊 -“活着或者去世的勇士”
I would love to.  "The brave men, living and dead...
但雷斯勒家必须办理交屋
I have an open house at the Ressler place.
“神圣，以致我们薄弱的力量 实不能再对它有所扬抑”
Have consecrated, far above our poor power to add or detract. "
难怪你看起来这么美
I guess that's why you look so nice.
长官！定位地址有状况
Chief! We got a problem with our location.
-那地方已经不存在了 -糟了！
It's no longer there.  Shit!
-还有多少时间？ -13分钟
Time frame?  Thirteen minutes.
联邦调查员来了
Investigator from the fed's here.
我没时间应付联邦菜鸟
I don't need some twink from the fed poking around.
我有帮你记在行事历上
I wrote it on your calendar.
查查报纸有没有改送其它地址
See if the neighbors knew where they went.
-也问一下邻居 -马上查！
Check all relations.  Checking.
倒杯咖啡给他，陪他哈拉
Just get him some coffee, tell him how I save your ass every day.
咖啡已经有了，谢谢
I got coffee, thanks.
丹尼威妥，联邦菜鸟
Danny Witwer, the twink from the fed.
要口香糖吗？
Oops. Gum?
我下次再带你参观
I'll give you the full tour some other time.
马克斯家上周搬家，下落不明
They moved two weeks ago. Nobody knows where. Still searching for family.
剩余时间：12分钟
Time horizon, 12 minutes.
他在鸡蛋里挑骨头 想办法找出凶案地点的线索
He's scrubbing the image, looking for...
...clues as to where the murder will happen.
原始砖砌墙，早期乔治亚式 砖缝经过特殊处理
Original running bond brick pattern, Georgian details. Brick was repointed.
我们的国家 “在上帝庇佑下，万世昌隆”
And that this nation, under God, shall not perish from the earth.
受害者在这，凶手在这里
Victims are pronounced here, killers here.
除了姓名与日期 只有他们制作的影像
Beyond that, all we have to run on are the images that they produce.
-骑马的警察 -首府大厦附近？
Show a cop on horseback.  Near the Capitol?
-没有磁浮快艇系统 -购物中心？
No Maglev system.  The Mall?
乔治城
Georgetown.
防罪中心能在四天前预知凶案 为什么这么晚才通知？
The PreCogs can see a murder four days out. Why the late call?
红球-冲动型犯罪 不是预谋，所以比较晚知道
A Red Ball. Crimes of passion have no premeditation, so they show up late.
突发事件占大多数 预谋犯罪已经很少见
Most of our scrambles are flash events. We rarely see premeditation anymore.
民众已经学乖了
People have gotten the message.
这个相当吻合 金斯利，十八世纪建筑师
I show a match with Dwight Kingsley, 18thcentury architect.
-在特区建造过24栋房子 -剩余时间：10分钟
He did two dozen houses in D.C.  Time horizon, 10 minutes.
看这小孩
Look at this kid.
他在这男人左边
In this one, he's on the left side of the man.
怎么样？所以呢？
Yes. So?
这里，他又在右边
This one he's on the right.
旋转木马
Merrygoround.
那是座公园！
It's a park.
特区只剩16座这种老旋转木马
There's only 16 of these old merrygorounds left in the city.
乔治城有两座 一座在巴纳比，一座在伍德利
Two in Georgetown, one in Barnaby Woods, the others in Woodley.
一定在巴纳比，飞行时间
It's gotta be Barnaby Woods. Evanna, flight time?
起飞后三分钟可以了
The way I drive? Three minutes after wheels up.
-可以了 -可以了
Clear.  Clear.
剩余时间：6分钟
Time horizon, six minutes.
上床去吧
Let's go to bed.
在这里就好啦
Let's do it in here.
-床比较软 -我的身体很软
But the bed is soft.  I'm soft.
糟了！
Shit.
哪一家？
Which one is it?
-我不喜欢这张床！ -来嘛
Not the bed.  Come on.
我不喜欢在床上玩！
I don't want to be on the bed.
-一分钟，快追上未来了 -闭嘴，艾文纳，杰德？
We're catching up to the future.  Shut up, Evanna. Jad?
-杰德？ -请讲
Jad?  Go ahead.
-他有关上前门吗？ -什么？
Did he close the front door?  What?
马克斯有关上前门吗？
Did Marks close the front door?
前门
Front door...
跟你说我不喜欢在床上玩
I didn't wanna be on the bed.
-开着，前门是开着的 -30秒
Negative. The front door is open.  Time horizon, 30 seconds.
我忘了眼镜
I forgot my glasses.
霍华！
Howard.
不戴眼镜我简直跟瞎子一样
You know how blind I am without them.
霍华，不要哭
Howard, don't cry.
马克斯！
Marks!
看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
确认是霍华马克斯
Positive for Howard Marks.
根据特区犯罪预防中心的授权
By mandate of the District of Columbia Precrime Division...
你因为即将谋害 莎拉马克斯和唐诺杜宝被捕
...you're under arrest for the future murder of Mrs. Marks and Mr. Dubin...
命案将于8点4分实际发生
...that was to take place today at 0800 hours and four minutes.
-我什么都没做，莎拉？ -给他戴上帽子
I didn't do anything. Sarah?  Give the man his hat.
不要给我戴那头铐！莎拉！
Oh, God. Don't put that halo on me. Sarah!
-手放在头上 -救救我！我什么都没打算做！
Put your hand on your head.  Help me! I wasn't gonna do anything!
我是防罪中心伤害应变小组
I'm Officer Scott with the Precrime Trauma Response Unit.
请你听我解释
Sit here a minute and listen to me.
你先生被犯罪防治中心警官逮捕
Your husband is being arrested by Precrime.
噢，霍华，不！
Oh, God, Howard, no.
霍华，不要哭 霍华，不要哭
Howard, don't cry. Howard, don't cry.
霍华，请不要哭 天啊，天啊
Please, don't cry. Oh, God. Oh, God.
命案不是被阻止了吗？
I thought they stopped the murder.
这是“回音”，或称“前视印象”
That's just an echo. PreCog deja vu, if you will.
预视者会不断看见发生的凶案
The really bad ones the PreCogs see over and over again.
华利，把剩下的洗掉
Wally, erase the incoming.
想象一个没有凶案的世界
Imagine a world without murder.
-我失去最好的朋友 -我失去姑姑
I lost my best friend.  I lost my aunt.
-我失去我父亲 -我太太惨遭杀害
I lost my dad.  I lost my wife.
六年前，美国凶案发生率 达到历史最高峰
Just six years ago, the homicide rate had reached epidemic proportions.
似乎只有奇迹才能终止这现象
It seemed that only a miracle could stop the bloodshed.
奇迹诞生了，而且有三个 犯罪预视先知
But instead of one miracle, we were given three: The PreCognitives.
犯罪预防条例实施一个月后
Within just one month under the Precrime program...
哥伦比亚区的凶案下降90%
...the murder rate in the District of Columbia was reduced 90%% .
-他们在等我 -他将会强暴我
They were waiting for me.  He was gonna rape me.
-我会被刺死 -这里
I was going to be stabbed.  Right here.
一年之内，犯罪预防中心 阻止了首府所有凶案
Within a year, Precrime effectively stopped murder in our nation 's capital.
实验计划进行六年来
In the six years of our experiment...
犯罪防治局局长
一桩命案都未曾发生
...there hasn't been a single murder.
现在犯罪防治局将正式成立
And now Precrime can work for you.
我们希望能够确定国人
We want to make certain that every American...
能信赖此系统的精确性
...can bank on the infallibility of the system.
在带来安全的同时 还能确保国人的自由
And to ensure that what keeps us safe will also keep us free.
-犯罪防治局-有效 -功效卓著
Precrime. It works.  It works.
-功效卓著 -功效卓著
It works.  It works.
犯罪防治局-有效！
Precrime. It works.
4月22日星期二，请投票赞成 国家犯罪防治局的成立
On Tuesday, April 22, vote "yes" on the National Precrime Initiative.
怎么回事？睡不着？
What's the matter? Can't sleep?
-我需要来点“冰品” -内行人
Just need a little clarity.  True that.
传统冰品还是改良的新配方？
You want the customary clarity or the new and improved kind of clarity?
新玩意儿
Give me the new stuff.
改良新配方，全新“冰品” 冰得你心旷神怡
New and improved clarity. Clarity, clarity. Yes, indeed.
快点，快点
Come on. Come on.
才四瓶，其中有的还没效
Don't bust my balls. You've only given me four, and some of these are duds.
祝你好梦，队长
Sweet dreams, chief.
别担心，我守口如瓶
Don't worry. Your secret's safe with me.
身边有个大人物也不错
I could use a little juice on my side.
你知道些什么？
What do you think you know?
我爸以前常说
It's like my daddy used to say:
“在瞎子的世界里
"In the land of the blind...
独眼龙足以当国王”
...the oneeyed man is king. "
我回来了
I'm home.
顶灯
Overhead.
电视墙
Wall screen.
-西恩！ -嗨，爸爸
Sean.  Hi, Daddy.
能不能教我跑快一点？
Can you teach me how to run faster?
班上同学跑得都比我快
Because all the kids in my class run faster than me.
这很好
That's good.
膝盖抬高一点
Keep your knees up.
像那样，高，再高
Like that. Like that. High. High. Like that.
-看到没，你是天生飞毛腿 -我一定要常练习跑步！
See, you're a natural runner.  Gotta keep running.
不断的跑吧
Yeah. Gotta keep running.
你要不断的跑
Gotta keep running.
-将来会跟你跑的一样快吗？ -有一天你会比我快
Will I be as fast as you someday?  Oh, I think you'll beat me someday.
-将来会比谁都快 -我想你将来会比谁都快
You're gonna beat everybody.  I think you'll beat everyone someday.
-我要走了，拜拜 -等等
I gotta go. Bye.  No, no, no. Wait, wait.
-给我亲一个 -不能亲嘴唇
You gotta give me a kiss.  Not on the lips.
那是妈妈的专利
Only Mommy kisses me on the lips.
好吧，好吧
Yeah, all right. All right.
我爱你
I love you.
-我爱你，西恩 -我爱你，爸爸
I love you, Sean.  I love you, Daddy.
档案结束
它让我想起罗赛里多海滩
Reminds me of Rosarito Beach.
记得吗？
Remember?
我们只有20元
We had 20 dollars and...
睡在车里等待日出 继续度假
Waiting in that van so the sun would shine on our vacation.
约翰！约翰！ 不要拍
John. John. John, put the camera down.
我准备要睡觉了 你在干嘛？拿走啦
Look, I'm all ready for bed. What is this? No. Put it away.
收起来
It's time to put the camera to sleep...
该照顾的是你老婆
...and time to come and take care of your wife.
不要拍啦，陪我看雨？
Why don 't you put the camera down and come and watch the rain with me?
不要？我会让你永生难忘喔
No? I promise I'll make it a memorable moment.
摄影机放下，不然今晚别碰我
Put the camera down or you're not getting anything tonight.
档案结束
司法部要把这系统拿走
A gentleman at Justice wants to take this away from us.
一星期后，民众将投票决定
In a week, people will vote on whether or not...
我们这儿执行的是高尚的工作
...what we've been doing has been a nobleminded enterprise...
一个改变打击犯罪方式的机会
...or a chance to change the way this country fights crime.
约翰
John...
注意这个丹尼威妥 司法部来的
...watch this Danny Witwer, the observer from Justice.
-我昨天见过他 -带他参观
I met him yesterday.  Let him look around.
回答他的问题 但，多留意点
Answer his questions, but watch him.
有问题的话，我们得先知道
If there's any problem, make sure we know about it.
被害人和凶手姓名刻在木球上
When the PreCogs declare a killer, their name is embedded in the wood.
因为每个球形状和纹理都不同 所以不可能被伪造
Since the shape and grain of each piece is unique, they're impossible to forge.
据我所知 犯罪预防理论在法理上有瑕疵
You understand the legalistic drawback to Precrime methodology.
-又来了 -我也不赞成人权协会的看法
Here we go again.  I'm not with the ACLU on this...
但还没犯法我们就先行逮捕
...but we arrest individuals who've broken no law.
-他们一定会犯罪 -预测完全依照物理法则
They will.  The commission is metaphysics.
先知预见未来，未曾有错
The PreCogs see the future, and they're never wrong.
阻止了，未来就不会发生
But it's not the future if you stop it.
-这岂不自相矛盾？ -没错
Isn't that a fundamental paradox?  Yes.
你说的就是必然性 这现象随处可见
You're talking about predetermination, which happens all the time.
-你为什么要抓住它？ -它快掉下去了
Why'd you catch that?  It was gonna fall.
你确定？
You're certain?
但它还没掉下去 就被你抓住了
But it didn't fall. You caught it.
虽被你阻止了，但一定会发生
Preventing it doesn't change the fact that it was going to happen.
曾经发生误判吗？
You ever get any false positives?
有人想杀妻，但没动手 先知分辨得出来吗？
Someone intends to kill, but doesn't. How do the PreCogs tell the difference?
先知看不见你的意图 只看见你即将做的事
They don't see what you intend to do, only what you will do.
为什么看不到强暴案 袭击或是自杀事件？
Why can't they see rapes, assaults, suicides?
谋杀的本质
Because of the nature of murder.
“伤害人类连系最盛者”
Nothing's more destructive to the metaphysical fabric that binds us...
-“莫过彼此间相互谋害” -不会是惠特曼的诗句吧
...than the untimely murder of a human.  That wasn't Walt Whitman.
是艾莉丝海曼 预视系统与接口的设计者
Iris Hineman. She developed PreCogs, designed the system and the interface.
提到接口，可以打个招呼吗？
Speaking of interfacing, I'd love to say hello.
-跟海曼？ -跟他们
To Hineman?  To them.
-警察禁止进入圣殿 -你没进去过？
Cops aren't allowed inside the temple.  You've never been inside?
保持隔离，以免被控干预办案
We keep strict separation so that no one can be accused of tampering.
-那我就是第一个进去的人 -你没听清楚吗？
I'll be the first one to go in then?  Maybe you didn't hear me.
-如果是权限问题 -不
If it's a question of authority...  There is no question.
你根本毫无权限
You don't have any.
我的搜索令上写的可不一样
I have a warrant in my pocket that says different.
-给我看 -没问题
Show it to me.  Sure.
针对犯罪预防中心的调查一事
This investigation of Precrime and its personnel is conducted...
直接受首席检察官的管辖和许可
...under the direct supervision and permission from the attorney general.
我在此是他的代表
I'm here as his representative...
也就是说 我现在是你的顶头上司
...which means you're now operating under my supervision.
看起来你不了解状况
Seems you've been left out of the loop.
准备好了，走吧
All right, we're ready. Let's go.
-站住 -不得进入
Hold it right there. Hold on.  Not cleared for access.
眼珠辨识 约翰安德顿，允许进入
Eyedent: John Anderton. Approved.
-华利 -不可以
Wally.  No, no, no, no.
这位是司法部来的丹尼威妥 他有权彻底视察
Danny Witwer from Justice. We're to give him the run of the farm.
-我不能碰到你！ -别碰他或任何东西
I can't touch you.  Don't touch anything.
-你不能进来 -回答他的问题，我们马上走
You can't be in here.  Just answer his questions.
-告诉我… -他们在睡觉
Tell me how...  They're sleeping.
对不起，介绍一下这里的作业
Sorry. Tell me how all this works.
光子乳液的功能是养分与导体
The photon milk acts as both a nutrient supply and conductor.
它会强化他们收到的影像 那位女性叫亚嘉莎
It enhances the images they receive. We call the female Agatha.
双胞胎是阿瑟和戴希尔 以光学断层摄影术作扫瞄
The twins are Arthur and Dashiell. We scan by way of optical tomography.
白色光点指示头盔内的脉动
Whitelight pinpoints pulse along the length of the headgear...
吸收脑波后再重新解读
...and are reread after absorption through their brain tissue.
换句话说，我们见其所见
In other words, we see what they see.
他们不会感到痛苦 我们持续供给多巴胺和恩多啡
They don't feel pain. We keep their heads stocked with dopamine.
此外，撒托宁也在控制中
Plus, we maintain careful control over their serotonin levels.
不能沉睡
Don't want them to drift off into too deep a sleep.
-也不能太清醒 -最好不要把他们当人类
They can't be kept too awake either.  Don't think of them as human.
不，他们伟大多了
No. They're much more than that.
奇迹大多被科学粉碎了
Science has stolen most of our miracles.
某方面说，他们给我们希望 对于神性的希望
In a way, they give us hope, hope of the existence of the divine.
有人开始将先知当成神
It's interesting that some people have begun to deify the PreCogs.
先知只是辨识模式的过滤器
PreCogs are patternrecognition filters. That's all.
-你们称这里为“圣殿” -只是个外号
Yet you call this room the "temple. "  A nickname.
权力不在神谕本身
The oracle isn't where the power is, anyway.
而在祭司，他们甚至假造神谕
The power is with the priests, even if they had to invent the oracle.
你们点头，好像懂他的意思
You guys are nodding like you know what he's talking about.
队长，我们改变命运的做法
Well, come on, chief. The way we work, changing destiny and all...
根本像神职人员而不是警察
...we're more like clergy than cops.
-杰德 -是的？
Jad.  Yeah?
去工作 全部去
Go to work. All of you.
对不起，老习惯
Sorry. Old habit.
当警察前，我念过三年神学院
I spent three years at Fuller Seminary before I became a cop.
-我父亲感到十分光荣 -他现在怎么想？
My father was proud.  What does he think of your work?
不知道，我15岁时 他在都柏林的教堂被杀
I don't know. He was shot and killed when I was 15 at our church in Dublin.
我知道失去亲人的感受
I know what it's like to lose someone close.
但失去儿子最为痛苦
Nothing's like the loss of a child.
我没有孩子，只能靠想象
I don't have any children, so I can only imagine what that was like.
在公共场所失去儿子的感觉
To lose your son in such a public place like that...
至少这种事不会再发生了
Now we can make sure that kind of thing doesn't happen to anyone.
-废话少说，你想找什么？ -瑕疵
Tell me what it is you're looking for.  Flaws.
六年内没有谋杀案，系统十分…
There hasn't been a murder in six years. This system is...
完美，我同意，瑕疵出在人
Perfect. I agree. If there's a flaw, it's human.
不变的真理
It always is.
约翰
John.
华利
Wally.
你看到了吗？
Can you see?
发生什么事？ 她的肾上腺素破表了
What happened? Her ACTH levels just shot through the roof!
-你对她做了什么？ -她抓住我
What'd you do?  She grabbed me.
不可能，先知只看得见未来 感觉不到我们的存在
Impossible. They're not aware of us. In the milk, all they see is the future.
-她盯着我看 -作恶梦吧？他们会梦见旧凶案
She looked straight at me.  It could have been a nightmare.
-她跟我说话 -跟你说？
She spoke to me.  To you?
她说什么？
What'd she say?
“你看到了吗？”
"Can you see?"
（看守所）
你是所长？
You the sentry?
是的，长官，我叫吉狄恩
Yes, sir, I'm Gideon.
你是安德顿队长
You're Chief Anderton.
音乐能使犯人放松
The music relaxes the prisoners.
防罪中心警察不曾来过 有问题吗？
I don't ever see you Precops down here. Am I in trouble?
还不确定，来查一桩凶案
Not yet. I'm interested in a murder.
-多得很，哪种手法？ -溺毙
I got plenty of those. Kill type?  Drowning.
这种倒不多
That narrows it down. Not too many in here for that.
-白种女性受害人 -这跟司法部有关吗？
Victim's Caucasian, female.  This about the Justice Department?
我明天出差，这领带怎么样？
I'm supposed to spruce up for a tour they got tomorrow. You like this tie?
停
Stop.
倒回去
Roll back.
这里！
There.
早期著名的案子 也许在你到任以前
She's a golden oldie. One of our first. Probably before your time.
-这是三位先知的共同档案？ -对
This is the composite of the three?  That's right.
三份影像综合起来播放
Combined data stream based on all three previsions.
-给我看亚嘉莎的 -这个嘛
Just show me Agatha's data stream.  For that...
我们得去找一找
...we go for a ride.
我的天
My God.
我忘了关了这么多人
I'd forgotten there were so many.
要不是你，他们还四处杀人
And to think they'd all be out there killing people if it wasn't for you.
你看看，看起来多祥和
Look at them. Look at how peaceful they seem.
但心里头可忙得很
But on the inside: Busy, busy, busy.
对了，这里有个大坏蛋
Okeypokey. Now that is one bad man.
他在罗兰湖杀了安莉芙丽
He drowned a woman named Anne Lively out at Roland Lake.
凶手身份一直是个谜
The killer's a John Doe, never identified.
为什么还查不出来？ 眼珠扫瞄也无法辨认？
Why is he still a John Doe? Why wasn't he ID'd from the eye scan?
他跟别人换眼珠，欺骗扫瞄器
Those are not his eyes. He had them swapped out to fool the scanners.
花几千块，到处可以做
You can get it done on the street for a few thousand bucks these days.
你只要女先知的影像
Okay, so you want just the female prevision.
对
That's right.
好像没有她的资料
We don't seem to have her data.
再找一次
Try again.
奇怪，看
This is odd. See?
其它两份都在 阿瑟和戴希的影像都在
We have the two previsions. We got what Art saw. We got what Dash saw.
但亚嘉莎的却不见了
But Agatha's isn't here.
可能系统出了小问题
Probably just a glitch.
跟我谈谈安莉芙丽
Tell me about the intended victim, this Anne Lively.
她跟这位无名氏一样 有“纽洛因”毒瘾
Looks like she's a neuroin addict, like our John Doe here.
但她住过毕顿勒戒所
Address history includes the Beaton Clinic.
所以她戒了，她现在住哪？
So she cleaned up. Where is she now?
失踪
又出问题，有一就有二
I guess glitches come in twos.
正所谓厄运接踵而至
You finally crawl your way out of one hole just to fall into another.
不行
No.
我不能让你带走，队长
Can't let you take that out of here, chief.
-违反规定 -我看这里违反规定的事不少
It's against the rules.  Anything else against the rules?
小心，挖出陈年往事 只会越弄越脏
Careful, chief. You dig up the past, all you get is dirty.
第三份影像呢？模糊不清？
The third prevision was what, kind of fuzzy or something?
第三份，亚嘉莎的不在里面
No, the third prevision, Agatha's prevision, wasn't there.
还不只如此 我发现许多案子都有影像失踪
That's not all. There are a dozen more cases with missing previsions.
怎么到现在还没有感冒特效药
You'd think we'd have found the cure for the common cold.
-你压力太大 -这是什么东西？
It's stress.  What's this?
加蜂蜜的青草茶
Herbal tea with honey.
青草茶和蜂蜜我都讨厌
I hate herbal tea. Almost as much as I hate honey.
快喝，不然倒在你腿上
Just drink it, before I pour it in your lap.
-喝点什么吗，约翰？ -不用，谢谢
Can I get you anything, John?  No, thank you.
威妥明天也计划参观看守所
Witwer's scheduled for a tour of Containment tomorrow.
对，带他去
Yeah, give him a tour.
-劳拉打电话给我 -什么？
Lara called me.  What?
她担心你，说实话，我也担心
She's worried about you. Quite frankly, so am I.
我没问题
I'm fine.
我知道你常到贫民区
I understand you've been spending a lot of time in the Sprawl.
-跑步经过罢了 -三更半夜？
I go running down there.  In the middle of the night.
万一威妥要验你的尿怎么办？
What if Danny Witwer insisted on a full chem run?
没问题
I'm fine.
约翰，防罪中心变国家机构后 他们会把它抢走
The minute Precrime goes national, they are going to take it away.
-我们不会坐视它发生 -不会？
We won't let them.  No?
一个老头 和一个嗑药条子怎么阻止他们？
How is an old man and a cop on the whiff ever going to stop them?
我老头说过
My father once said to me...
“不是你选择爱做的事 是事情选择你”
..."You don't choose the things you believe in. They choose you. "
你在此有其原因
There's a reason you are here.
假如预知犯罪早半年成立
你和劳拉便不用承担如此悲痛
Had Precrime been in place earlier, your loss would have been prevented.
记住，全国人的眼睛…
Remember, the eyes...
全国现在都盯着我们看
The eyes of the nation are on us right now.
我是说话没人听的老家伙
I'm not the generation anyone listens to...
但民众相信你 如果你说对犯罪预防有信心
...but people trust you when you speak of your belief in Precrime.
他们相信那是肺腑之言 不是政治辞令，我早就知道
They know that it's a belief born of pain, not politics. I understood that.
我也曾促成这件事
I may have even encouraged it to help with the cause.
但是，你的伤痛伤害了我们
But now, your pain is hurting both of us.
他们抢不走的
They're not going to take it away from us.
我不允许
I won't let them.
抓到了
Bingo.
-嗨，爸 -嗨，儿子
Hi, Daddy.  Hey, buddy.
-我创立了一个社团 -是吗？
I made up a club.  Yeah?
-叫做克里斯戈 -克里斯戈
We're called the Crescos.  The Crescos.
-组成足球队 -是吗？
We made up a soccer team.  Yeah?
-在学校练球 -跟康诺练吗？
We practice at school.  With Connor?
爸爸麻烦大了，西恩
Your daddy's in a lot of trouble, Sean.
（被害者） （里欧克罗）
-等等！ -不！
Wait!  No!
你怎么没陪着威妥神父？
Jad, how come you're not with Father Witwer?
要出勤了，被害者的特征
白种男性，大约5尺10寸，170磅
We're in motion on something. We got a white, male victim, about 5' 10", 170.
胸腹部中弹
He takes a round in the 10ring and goes out a window.
-红球吗？ -不，棕球
Red Ball?  Nope. Brown Ball.
预谋犯罪
It's premeditated.
还有人笨得敢预谋
Amazing. There's someone within 200 miles still dumb enough to do that.
被害人里欧克罗
The victim's name is Leo Crow.
案号1109 发生时间：周五下午3点6分
This is case number 1109. Time of occurrence: Friday, 1506 hours.
开始搜寻未来被害人里欧克罗 1109案已被先知看见
Start search for Leo Crow. Case 1109, previsualized by the PreCogs...
影像纪录于本中心系统目录
...recorded on holosphere by Precrime's Qstacks.
共同见证人有凯瑟琳詹姆士 和法兰克波勒审判长
My fellow witnesses are Dr. Katherine James and Chief Justice Frank Pollard.
早安
Good morning.
见证人愿授权侦办案吗？
Are you ready to preview and validate 1109?
-随时待命 -待命中
Ready when you are, John.  Standing by.
我喜欢这段工作
I love this part.
找不到住址 过去五年不曾报税
I've got no address. No tax returns for the last five years.
或许国家犯罪数据中心有纪录
Check NCIC. Maybe he's got a number.
锁定住址后 派一支保护队过去
We'll send a protection team as soon as we lock location.
好像联邦宿舍的钢筋铁笼建筑
It looks like federal housing. Concrete, glass, egg crates.
本区大概有上千栋
Ouch. About a thousand of those in the District.
零碎画面陆续送达
Fractured images coming in.
数字9…
Numbers nine...
9和6
Nine, six.
女性，老人，抽烟斗
Female, senior. She's smoking a pipe.
她在笑
She's laughing.
现在在室内
Okay, now I'm inside a room.
方格窗，铝条制
Windowpanes, aluminum extrusion.
房间内有两个人形
Two figures resolving in the room.
-等等！ -不
Wait!  No...
有第三者
Looks like we got a third party.
带太阳眼镜，在窗外
Wearing sunglasses, just out the window.
你杀不了我
You're not gonna kill me.
再见，克罗
Goodbye, Crow.
你杀不了我
You're not gonna kill me.
-再见，克罗 -等等！
Goodbye, Crow.  Wait!
等一下，等一下
Wait. Wait.
你说什么，队长？
You say something, chief?
没有
No.
我来拿这颗
I'll get this one.
这案子时间很充裕
We got time on this one, Jad.
帮我拿块蛋糕
Mind getting me a piece of cake they're eating?
-我好饿 -好
I'm starving.  Sure, chief.
我自己也要一块
I think I'll get one for myself too.
慢慢来
Take your time.
（约翰安德顿）
安德顿队长，我正在看什么？
Chief Anderton, what is this that I'm seeing?
我有点胡涂了…
I'm confused about...
-安德顿，等等！ -再见，克罗
Anderton, wait!  Goodbye, Crow.
安德顿，等等！
Anderton, wait!
我喜欢你，队长，你对我不错
I like you, chief. You've always been nice to me.
按警铃前，我给你两分钟
Give you two minutes before I hit the alarm.
请等我一下
Hold that, please.
谢谢
Thanks.
-你麻烦大了 -你设计我
You're in a lot of trouble, John.  You set me up.
我会将你的妄想症归咎于毒品
I'll write the paranoia off to the whiff you've been doping on.
慢慢来
Easy.
-慢慢来 -我似乎找到瑕疵了
Easy.  Seems I've found a flaw.
你想怎么办？
What are you gonna do?
拥有毒品判六个月，外加解职
Possession will cost you six months and your badge.
看来我们当不成同事了
I guess we won't be working together after all.
枪放下，别搞成红球状况
Now put the gun down, John. I don't hear a Red Ball.
拉玛？拉玛？
Lamar. Lamar.
-拉玛？ -约翰，怎么回事？
Lamar?  John, what is happening?
威妥！他设计我！
It's Witwer. He set me up!
等等
Stop, just wait.
-一定是威妥！ -被害人是谁？
Witwer! It's Witwer.  Who's the victim?
-某个人 -是谁？
Somebody.  Who?
-里欧克罗 -他是什么人？
Somebody... Leo Crow.  Who is he?
我怎么知道！连听都没听过
I have no idea! I've never heard of him.
而36小时后我会杀死他
But I'm supposed to kill him in less than 36 hours.
-威妥怎么能读取案件档案？ -你可以伪造脑部输出吗？
How could Witwer have access?  Can you fake a cerebral output?
-谁想要？ -你能不能？
Why would anyone want to?  Can you?
-我很怀疑 -海曼知不知道？
I doubt it.  Would Hineman know?
-你先过来 -什么？
Now listen, come in.  What?
真相大白前我保护你的安全
I'll protect you until we get to the bottom of this.
查查威妥是否又进去过圣殿
Talk to Wally. See if Witwer's gone inside the temple again.
问杰德，下班后 分析室有没有眼珠扫瞄纪录？
Ask Jad for any offhour eyedents into the analytical room.
跟我说，谁是里欧克罗？
Who's Leo Crow?
功能锁定 返回办公室
Security lockdown enabled. Revised destination: Office.
他们发现了
Lamar, they found me.
有没有办法解除锁定？
Is there any way to override the lockdown?
-不，不 -不？
No, no, no.  No?
随便在哪见面，先到我家
I'll meet you anywhere you say. You can come to my house, John.
我会在那被抓，我不想戴头铐
I can't. They'll get me. I'm not gonna get haloed.
你逃不掉的
You can't run.
每个人都会逃
Everybody runs.
-天啊 -喂，喂
Oh, my God!  Hey, hey.
哇
噢，你还好吧？
Oh, my gosh, are you okay?
我会把他毫发无伤地逮捕归案
I'll bring him in. Unharmed.
高登，不必了，小组由我接管
You're not gonna do that. I'm taking control.
什么？
What?
佛莱契是第二指挥官 让他表现一下，你从旁观察
Fletcher is second in command. It's his show to run. You can observe.
-动手，去找他 -是的，长官
Do it. Find him.  Yes, sir.
事发前一天他来找你
He came to see you the other day right before he was tagged.
-你们谈些什么？ -职棒
What did you talk about?  The Mets.
他们今年投手群不强
John doesn't think they have a deep enough pitching roster.
你为什么护着他？ 你知道他在嗑药
Why are you protecting him? You knew he was doping, yet you did nothing.
-他失去一个孩子 -六年前的事
The man lost a child, for chrissake.  Six years ago.
-你们谈些什么？ -不关你的事
What did you talk about?  None of your business.
现在全都跟我有关了 警官涉及重罪的调查
It's my business. Investigation of a supervising officer for a capital crime...
由联邦警方负责，以免有同谋
...falls under federal jurisdiction so as to rule out any conspiracy.
-他是我的嫌犯 -他是我的属下
He's my suspect.  He's my subordinate.
问检察总长，由他厘清权责
Call the attorney general. I'm sure he'd clarify the issue for you.
我不想安德顿受到伤害
I don't want John Anderton hurt.
我会在这儿胜任愉快
I'm going to enjoy working here.
沙漠中的岔路
A road diverges in the desert.
Lexus
Lexus.
你选择的一条，约翰安德顿 是少数菁英走的路
The road you're on, John Anderton, is the one lesstraveled.
-确定你… -钻石
Make sure you...  Diamonds...
晚安，约翰安德顿！
Good evening, John Anderton.
约翰安德顿 即刻享受一杯金氏黑啤酒
John Anderton! You could use a Guinness right about now.
-约翰安德顿 -远离烦嚣吧
John Anderton...  Escape from it all.
度个假吧，约翰安德顿 忘掉一切烦恼
Get away, John Anderton. Forget your troubles.
他在大都会地铁 列车停两站，20街和33街
He's been eyedented on the Metro. The train stops at 20th and 33rd.
两站都派警力
Send units to each location.
-20街来不及 -要有信心
Better make 20th.  Have faith.
（新闻快报）
（犯罪预防中心猎捕自家人）
启动喷射背心！
Fire them up!
-嘿，佛莱契 -嘿，约翰
Hey, Fletch.  Hey, John.
-降落得不太漂亮 -是啊
That was a rough landing.  Yeah.
-你要多练习 -我的膝盖不太好
Work on that.  It's the shit knee of mine.
-哦 -不要逃
Yeah.  Don't do it.
嘿，不要逃
Hey, don't do this.
约翰？
John?
不要逃
Don't run.
你没必要追我
You don't have to chase me.
你没必要逃
You don't have to run.
每个人都会逃，佛莱契
Everybody runs, Fletch.
我们会逮到你
You know we'll catch you.
每个人都会逃
Everybody runs.
-没必要搞得很难看 -每个人都会逃
It doesn't have to be like this, John.  Everybody runs.
催吐棒准备好
Get your sicksticks ready.
每个人都会逃，佛莱契
Everybody runs, Fletch.
慢慢来，队长，别冲动
Slow down, chief. Just take it easy.
别轻举妄动，队长
No sudden moves, chief.
约翰，没事的
John, it's okay.
-佛莱契… -冷静，别冲动
Fletch...  Easy does it, chief.
抓牢了吗？
Got a grip?
-抓牢了吗？ -抓牢了
Got a grip?  Yeah.
安德顿！
Anderton!
滚出我的厨房！
Go away! Get out of my kitchen!
滚出去！出去！
Get out of my house! Get out of my house! Go!
-出去！ -安德顿，住手！
Get them out of here!  Anderton, stop!
拉他下来，佛莱契
Pull him off me, Fletcher. Get him off me.
滚出去！听不懂吗？
Get him out of here! What's the matter with you?!
滚出去！快！
Get out of my house! Go!
根据特区犯罪预防中心授权 你被逮捕…
By mandate of the District of Columbia, I'm placing you under arrest for...
睡一觉吧
Go to sleep.
跟我来
You two stay with me!
（非请勿入）
海曼博士？
Dr. Hineman.
你私闯民宅，我不接待访客
You're trespassing. I don't have visitors.
你中了娃娃眼的毒，它的藤蔓
That would be from the doll's eye, the vine...
在你攀墙进来时划破你的皮
...the baneberry that scratched you during your illegal climb over my wall.
不是纯娃娃眼 我培育的混种，蛮厉害的
It's not a true doll's eye. It's a little hybrid I designed.
一旦毒液进入血管
Once the poison gets into your bloodstream, you'll start to see...
你会开始看到 蓝色物体的神奇景象
...the most extraordinary display of blue objects.
这星期倒霉透了吧？
This just isn't your week, is it?
安德顿队长
Chief Anderton.
我不是凶手
I'm not a killer.
喝下去
You better drink this.
不然你会无法吞咽 然后就完蛋了
Soon you won't be able to swallow, and then you'll be totally buggered.
全部喝掉
All of it.
休息一分钟回回神
Okay, now take a minute to right yourself.
你认为我能帮什么忙？
Just what is it you think I can do for you?
告诉我如何 伪造预视影像？
You could tell me how someone can fake a prevision.
我怎么知道？
How would I know that?
因为系统是你发明的
Because you invented Precrime.
有什么好笑的？
What's so funny?
如果基因学上的一个错误 加上科学上的失控
If the consequences of several genetic mistakes and science gone haywire...
叫发明 那么算我发明的
...can be called an invention, then I invented Precrime.
-你不引以为荣？ -不
You don't seem proud.  I'm not.
我想治疗他们，不是加以变造
I was trying to heal them, not turn them into something else.
-治疗谁？ -现在被用来阻止犯罪的人
Heal who?  The innocents we use to stop the guilty.
你是指先知
You're talking about the PreCogs.
你以为他们是试管做出来的？ 他们是侥幸存活者
You think they came from a test tube? They are merely the ones who survived.
我研究吸毒者后代的基因问题
I was doing genetic research, treating children of drug addicts.
十年前，纽洛因刚问世
This was 10 years ago, when neuroin first hit the streets.
成分不纯，粗制滥造的药品 大受知识分子的欢迎
It was impure, not the engineered cocktail popular among the educated.
那些孩子天生脑部受创 大部分12岁以前就死了
All of these kids were born with severe brain damage. Most died before age 12.
少数活下来的有种天赋
Those few who survived, they had a gift.
我称之为天赋，对他们来说 像是上帝开了个大玩笑
I call it a gift. For them, it was more like a cosmic joke.
他们会半夜醒来尖叫
They would wake up in the night, curled in the corner...
乱抓壁纸，因为…
...screaming, clawing at the walls.
他们晚上一闭上眼睛
Because when these children closed their eyes at night...
会梦见凶杀案，一桩接一桩
...they dreamt only of murder over and over, one after the other.
我们不久就发现 这些所谓的梦
It didn't take for us long to realize that the real nightmare was...
都成了事实 那些凶杀案实际发生了
...that these dreams were about to come true, these murders were happening.
你说其中一些孩子死了？
You say some of the children died?
很多，尽管我们尽力治疗
So many of them. Despite what we did for them.
或许正因为我们的疗法而死 但，无所谓啦
Or maybe because of what we did to them. But it doesn't matter.
系统很完美，不是吗？
It's a perfect system now, isn't it?
我不可能谋杀别人
I'm not going to commit murder.
我与要杀的人从未谋面
I've never met the man I'm supposed to kill.
但一连串的事件发生之后 会导致你去谋杀他
And yet a chain of events has started that will lead you to his murder.
-我会躲着他 -怎么躲？你不认识他
Not if I stay away from him.  Can you avoid a man you've never met?
-你不帮我？ -我没办法，谁都没办法
You won't help?  I can't help you. Nobody can.
先知从未发生错误
The PreCogs are never wrong.
话说回来，偶尔
But occasionally...
他们也会意见相左
...they do disagree.
什么？
What?
大多数时候 三个先知看到的都一样
Most of the time, all three PreCogs will see an event in the same way...
偶尔，其中之一会不同
...but once in a while, one of them will see things differently than the others.
天啊，我怎么不知道？
Jesus Christ. Why didn't I know about this?
因为这些关键报告都被毁了
Because these Minority Reports are destroyed the instant they occur.
为什么？
Why?
犯罪预防中心想继续运作 就不能让人觉得不可靠
For Precrime to function, there can't be any suggestion of fallibility.
司法系统容不得丝毫怀疑
Who wants a justice system that instills doubt?
尽管合理，却仍旧是怀疑
It may be reasonable, but it's still doubt.
你是说我冤枉过好人？
Are you saying I've haloed innocent people?
我只是说那些被控谋杀罪名的人
I'm saying that every so often, those accused of a Precrime...
也许会有不一样的未来
...just might have an alternate future.
伯吉斯知道关键报告的事吗？
Does Burgess know about this, about this Minority Report?
我跟拉玛开过玩笑 我们是防罪中心的父母
I used to joke with Lamar that we were the parents of Precrime.
父母眼中的孩子总是完美的
Parents often see their children as they want them to be and not as they are.
回答我的问题： 拉玛知不知道关键报告？
Answer my question: Does Lamar Burgess know about the Minority Report?
当然知道
Yes, of course, he knew.
但当时我们两人觉得无伤大雅
But at the time, we felt their existence was an insignificant variable.
对你或许无关紧要
Insignificant to you, maybe.
但假如我冤枉过好人呢？
But what about those people that I put away with alternate futures?
-如果国人知道… -那么这套系统就会崩溃
My God, if the country knew...  The system would collapse.
-我对系统有信心 -是吗？
I believe in that system.  Do you really?
你想毁掉它
You wanna bring it down.
你会毁掉它 如果你有办法杀死一个人
You will bring it down if you manage to kill your victim.
那等于向大众公然宣示 预知犯罪无效
That'll be the most spectacular public display of how Precrime didn't work.
-我不会杀任何人 -希望你坚持下去
I'm not gonna kill anybody.  Hold that thought.
-我为什么要相信你？ -谁都不能相信
Why should I trust you?  You shouldn't trust anyone.
包括检察总长 他想将系统占为己有
Certainly not the attorney general, who wants it all for himself.
那位年轻联邦干员想篡你的位
And not the young federal agent, who wants your job.
老头也想保住自己毕生的结晶 谁都不能相信
Not even the old man who just wants to hang on to what he created.
只要找出关键报告
Don't trust anyone. Just find the Minority Report.
你说它们被毁了
You said the Minority Report is destroyed.
纪录被毁，原始报告还在
The record is destroyed. The original report still exists.
根据我的设计，报告产生时 它会储存在一个秘密而安全的地方
I designed it so the report is stored in a safe place, but not declared.
什么安全的地方？
What safe place is that?
有个最安全的地方
The safest place there is.
在哪里？
Where is it?
在先知的体内
Inside the PreCog who predicted it.
你只需要将它下载出来
All you have to do is download it, darling.
这么简单？
That's all, huh?
走进防罪中心办公室
Just walk into Precrime, get into the temple...
走进圣殿，侵入系统 下载关键报告
...somehow tap into these PreCogs and download this Minority Report.
-假如有这报告的话 -然后走出来
If you have one.  And then walk out.
实际上你得用跑的 不过没错，你必须这么作
Actually, you'll have to run out. But yes, that's what you have to do.
你疯了
You're insane.
还是你认为我疯了
Or you think I am.
在靠近犯罪中心前 我的眼珠早被扫瞄十几次！
I'll get eyescanned a dozen times before I get within 10 miles of Precrime.
俗语说，不入虎穴焉得虎子
Sometimes in order to see the light, you have to risk the dark.
身为警察，抱歉 解职警察
As a policeman... Excuse me, as a former policeman...
我相信你认识一些人
...I'm sure that you know all sorts of people...
可以在这方面上帮助你
...who can help you out in this regard.
很有趣，一切生物如此相似
It's funny how all living organisms are alike.
受到威胁时，压力降临时
When the chips are down, when the pressure is on...
每种生物只关心一件事
...every creature on the face of the earth...
只有一件事
...is interested in one thing and one thing only:
自己的生存
Its own survival.
去找关键报告
Find the Minority Report.
我怎么知道谁才有关键报告？
How do I even know which one has it?
三人中最有天赋那位
It's always in the more gifted of the three.
到底哪一位？
Which one is that?
女性
The female.
这里，房间里三个男人 被害人在这
We've got three men in a room. The victim is here...
约翰在这，不明男性站在窗外
...John is here, and this unidentified male, at the window.
邻近建筑显示是廉价公寓 但无法辨识地点
The adjacent building suggests public housing, which means...
-有几千栋这种建筑 -到处都是
There's thousands like this one.  They're everywhere.
我们还有22小时
But he doesn't go there to kill Crow for another 22 hours.
你不能坐约翰的椅子
This is Chief Anderton's space.
-他走了 -他会回来
He's not here.  He'll be back.
我很怀疑 我猜他躲在贫民窟里
I doubt that. I'm betting he's somewhere in the Sprawl.
躲开电子广告牌扫瞄身份的地方
He's smart enough to go where billboards can't ID him.
越少消费者就越少扫瞄器
There's fewer consumers, which means fewer scanners.
-他为什么不远走高飞？ -他自认为无辜
Why won't he just run?  Because he thinks he's innocent.
重点放在贫民窟
We concentrate on the Sprawl.
低空侦搜 搭配二支蜘蛛小组
We do flyovers in ships, with two spyder teams on the ground.
追踪任何有眼睛和心跳的生物
Thermal scan the entire area. Read anything with eyes and a heartbeat.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
毫无预警就开枪，我早知道了
Started blowing buttons for no reason whatsoever, and I knew that.
该死的感冒！
This damn cold.
别担心 即使我塞只死猫在你胸腔里
Don't worry. I could cut open your chest and sew a dead cat in there...
你也不会被感染 这抗生素十分厉害
...you wouldn't get an infection. Not with the antibios I'll shoot into you.
那我就放心了
That's comforting.
你知道 我不能只给你换新的虹膜
You do understand I can't just give you new irises?
请不要碰
Please, don't touch.
伤疤被扫瞄到，警铃就会响
Because the scanners would read the new scar tissue, alarms will go off...
带枪的大个子就会出现
...and large men with guns will appear.
那是什么东西？
What was that?
那是什么？
-麻醉剂，让你乖乖就范… -你习惯偷袭病患吗？
It's anesthesia. It's all downhill...  You always sneak up on your patients?
钱没赚到，我不会害你
You wouldn't break the hand of a violinist before the concert.
别紧张
Please, relax.
我必须把你的眼睛整个拿出来
All I'm trying to tell you is that I'll have to remove your eyes completely.
我知道
I know.
-然后换一对新的 -旧的我要保存起来
I have to replace them with new ones.  I know. But I wanna keep the old ones.
-为什么？ -身体发肤受之父母
Why?  Because my mother gave them to me.
你留着也没用，又不能卖
What's it to you? You can't resell them.
随便你，出钱的是你
Whatever you say. It's your money.
我美丽的助手凡艾可小姐
Let me introduce my gorgeous assistant, Miss Van Eyck.
-钱并不多 -能动用的只有这些
This is not a lot of money.  It's all that I could safely move.
好吧
Okay.
-你给我打哪种药？ -微笑剂
What did you give me?  Smile medicine.
告诉你也无妨 老朋友了
Tell you what, since we go way back...
我给你打个折扣
...why don't I give you my old pal discount? What do you say?
你不记得我了吧？
You don't remember me, do you?
-我们认识吗？ -认识
We know each other?  Yes, we do.
在哪认识？特区？
From where? D.C.?
-巴尔的摩，城东 -巴尔的摩？认识很久了？
Baltimore. The East Side.  Baltimore? We go way back.
所罗门艾迪医师，整形外科
Solomon P. Eddie, M.D. I was a plastic surgeon.
我专治烧伤病患，特别是女性
You remember? Specialized in burn victims, mostly women.
-我逮捕过你 -没错
I put you away.  Yeah, you did.
你还拍摄录像带
You made those tapes.
业余表演艺术
They were performance pieces.
-那些病患是你放的火 -我也灭火！
You set your patients on fire.  I put them out.
有些人跑得不够快，换个话题
Some not as quickly as others, but let's change the subject, shall we?
未来比过去有趣多了 不是吗？
The future's so much more interesting than the past, don't you think?
恐怕凡艾可小姐爱上你了
Miss Van Eyck. I'm afraid she's already smitten.
她一直盯着你的“眼睛”
She only has eyes for you.
你一定在想，我怎么愿意帮你？
I know what you're thinking, John: How can I do what I do now?
我花很多时间在监狱图书馆
Let's say that I spent an awful lot of time in the prison library.
那是逃避监狱生活的好办法
That was a great way to avoid the more unpleasant aspects of prison life.
囚禁是真正的教育
Confinement was a real education, a real...
真正教人大开“眼”界
...eyeopener.
那是真正的启蒙，有什么比得上…
For true enlightenment, there's nothing quite like...
例如跟凶狠的重罪犯一起淋浴
...well, let's say, taking a shower while this large fellow...
高大到拿一把铁锤也打不倒 听他在你耳边呢喃…
...with an attitude you can't knock down with a hammer...
“噢，南希”
...whispers in your ear, "Oh, Nancy. "
好玩喔，多谢你让我入狱
That was a lot of fun. Thank you for putting me there...
拓展我的生命领域
...and giving me the opportunity to get to know myself so much better.
为了答谢你的恩泽
And now to return the favor.
-你的作品？ -是的
This your work?  Yes.
我很喜欢
I like it.
-咖啡要加什么？ -奶精和糖
How do you take your coffee?  Cream and sugar.
-我没有奶精 -糖就可以
I don't have any cream. Sorry.  Just sugar then.
-你跟约翰常来？ -以前
You and John ever come here?  We used to.
他现在不在这里吧？
He's not here now, is he?
我不得不问
I had to ask.
-糖也没有了 -谢谢
I don't have any sugar either.  Thank you.
-他没跟你联络？ -没有
He hasn't tried to contact you?  No.
他有没有提过里欧克罗？
Did he ever mention the name Leo Crow?
没有，我已不太跟约翰通话
No, but I don't talk to John much anymore.
-没看过他住的地方？ -那是我们以前的家
So you haven't seen his apartment.  That was our apartment.
最近有去吗？到处都是这玩意
Have you been there recently? It's full of these.
-他嗑药多久了？ -从失去我们的儿子以后
How long has he been doping?  Since right after we lost our son.
你是说他弄丢你的儿子以后？
那不是谁的错
You mean after he lost your son.  It was nobody's fault.
但是，当时约翰 也在公共游泳池陪他
But John was with him at the public pool.
离婚书上，你说约翰企图自杀
You said in your divorce papers that John tried to kill himself.
-那并不是自杀，我很后悔 -不然约翰做了什么？
It wasn't a suicide attempt.  What was it then?
FBI找到我儿子的凉鞋
The FBI found something that belonged to my son, a sandal.
约翰很激动…
John was upset. He...
他拿着枪看家庭录像带
He took out his gun and watched home movies.
-文件上都写着 -天花板被他打个洞，又怎样？
This is all in your statement.  He shot a hole in the ceiling. So what?
换做你，你会怎么样？
You lose your son, let's see how well you handle it.
你离开约翰是因为 他埋首在防罪中心的工作里
Lamar thinks you left John because he lost himself in Precrime instead of you.
我离开他是因为 一看到他，我就想到儿子
I left him because every time I looked at him, I saw my son.
靠近他就闻到我儿子的味道
Every time I got close to him, I smelled my little boy.
所以我才离开他
That's why I left him.
你可以走了
And now you can leave.
12小时内绷带不要拿掉
Don't take the bandages off for 12 hours.
拿下会瞎掉，懂吗？
If you take them off before then, you'll go blind. Understand?
冰箱有牛奶 葛莉塔为你做了个三明治
In the fridge, there's milk. Greta made you a sandwich.
多喝水
Make sure you drink a lot of water.
怎么找洗手间？
How do I find the bathroom?
洗手间？右手那条线
The bathroom? Now that's your right hand.
左手的是厨房
The kitchen is your left.
不要抓，千万不要抓！
Don't scratch. Never scratch!
看老朋友份上，送你个礼物
Seeing as we're being pals, I'll give you a bonus that may come in handy.
短效麻痹酵素，注射在下巴
This is a temporary paralytic enzyme. You're gonna shoot this under your chin.
-这是什么东西？ -它会让你的脸肿得像猪头
What is this?  It'll turn your pretty face into mush.
别人就认不出来了
People won't even recognize you.
30分钟后恢复正常 但你会痛不欲生
In 30 minutes, it'll tighten up again. But it'll hurt like you've never felt.
我把它放进你的宝贝袋
I'm gonna put this in your goodybag, together with your...
跟老眼珠放一起
...leftovers.
我定个时间，明天铃响 拆绷带离开
I'm setting up a timer. When it rings, you can remove the bandages and leave.
-不能提早，不然… -会瞎掉，我知道
But not before then, or you will...  Go blind. I know.
不要抓
Don't scratch.
我们共同的朋友送的小礼物
A little something from a mutual friend of ours.
12小时内不要拆绷带
Don 't take the bandages off for 12 hours.
提早拆会瞎掉，懂吧？
If you take them off before then, you'll go blind. Understand?
-2516秒，新纪录 -是世界纪录吗？
25. 16 seconds. That's a new record.  Is that a world record?
世界纪录？个人最佳成绩
Is it a world record? It's a personal best.
-换我帮你计时 -你在开玩笑
Now I wanna time you.  You gotta be kidding.
我不可能打破2516秒
There's no way I can beat 25. 16 seconds.
鲸鱼可以憋气多久？
How long can a whale hold its breath?
大约20分钟
For about 20 minutes.
-我们来打破鲸鱼的纪录 -好
So we gotta beat the whale.  Okay.
我们来打破鲸鱼的纪录
We gotta beat the whale.
拿着
Here you go.
20分钟，要不要去买冰淇淋？
It's gonna be 20 minutes. You sure you don't wanna go for an ice cream?
因为我要打破鲸鱼的纪录
Because you know I'm gonna beat that whale.
-好了吗？ -帮我倒数
Ready?  Give me the count.
3，2，1，开始
Three, two, one, go!
西恩？
Sean?
Sean.
你们有没有看到
Have you seen...?
我在找儿子，他穿红色泳裤
I'm looking for my son. Have you seen a boy in a red bathing suit?
你们有看到我儿子吗？ 他穿红色泳裤
You seen my boy? He's wearing a red bathing suit.
警网最前线
杰德，准备热感扫瞄 北鲍威尔街的所有住户
Jad, we're ready to begin thermal scan on all residences on North Powell.
你一定很喜欢我，佛莱契？
You must really like me, don't you?
所以你要我在这任务上搭档
That's why you asked to partner with me on this sortie.
我觉得你是好同事
You're swell company.
还是说你信不过我和老队长？
It's not that you don't trust me to be alone with the chief, is it?
你觉得我会和他聊天闲晃？
That you think I might, you know, futz with him?
我只想看他抓着你 撞破另一栋建筑物
No, I just wanna watch him use your body to sandblast another building.
艾文纳，开始
Evanna, go.
显示有27个温热物体
I show 27 warm bodies.
收到，27个温热物体
Roger that. Confirmed, 27 warm bodies.
-四只蜘蛛？每层楼一只？ -放八只，我想早点吃饭
Four spyders, one per floor?  Let's do eight. I gotta eat.
931鲍尔街居民注意 这是预知犯罪中心的佛莱契警官
Residents of 931 Powell, this is Officer Fletcher of D.C. Precrime.
根据犯罪防治法条授权 我们派遣蜘蛛搜索大楼
Under authority of P.C. section 6409, we are deploying spyders into your complex.
妈妈，我好害怕
Mom, I'm scared.
妈妈，我好害怕，妈妈
Mommy, I'm scared. Mommy.
眼睛张开，躺着不要动
That's gonna scan you. Keep your eyes open. Stay still.
-不要动 -很讨厌
It's okay.  I don't like it.
不要动，不要动
Stay still. Stay still.
来！
Come on!
你又出去偷腥！
You stepped out on me for the last time.
我跟你说过我去了哪里！
I told you where I was.
骗子！你昨晚跟那婊子在一起
You're a nogood liar. I know you was with that ho.
你很幸运我们…
You're lucky we...
不要再烦了！
Leave me alone!
一个不见了
We lost one.
收到，可能是猫跳过窗户
Roger that. Maybe it was a cat jumping through a window.
这猫还真大
It's an awful big cat.
佛莱契
Fletcher.
我去看看
I'll go check it out.
他们哭了！太恐怖了！
They're crying their eyes out. You terrified them.
靠近我，他们更会吓死
Keep your kids away from me.
等等，大猫回来了 可能是醉汉，醒不过来
The big cat's back. What do you think? A drunk, maybe can't wake up?
也可能是某人想躲过搜查
Or a guy who doesn't want to get read.
请安静，回到室内
Folks, be quiet, go back inside.
安静，把门关上！
Be quiet and close the door.
查出身份了，不是他
We got an ID. It's not him.
-不要太张扬 -去吃饭吧
Standing down.  Let's eat.
佛莱契，你来看看
Fletcher, take a look.
房间里有四人，不是三人
There's four people in this room, not three.
四人？安德顿，克罗 和一个戴太阳眼镜的人
Four? There's Anderton, Crow and the man in sunglasses.
他就是外面戴太阳眼镜那位
The man in the sunglasses is outside the window.
这里还有一个人 在镜子里
There's also someone here in the mirror.
确定是女性
Definitely female.
犯罪防治项目经联邦政府同意 在2046年开始施行
The Precrime program began in 2046 with a federal grant.
经过九年后，哥伦比亚区 成了美国最安全的城市
And now, nine years later, D.C. is the safest city in America.
为什么？因为犯罪防治有效
Why? Because Precrime works.
它取代了传统的警察系统
Precrime has eliminated the need for conventional detectives.
未来受害者被预知并受保护
What happens now is the verification and protection of future victims.
可以看看先知吗？
Can we see the PreCogs?
先知天生具有强大能力 他们必须处在与世隔绝的环境
They have such a powerful gift, they're kept in peaceful seclusion...
以免受到外界的干扰
...so as not to be distracted.
这里可以看到他们的生活
This display should give you some idea of what their daily life is like.
先知每年收到八百万封信
The PreCogs get over 8 million letters every year.
比圣诞老公公收到的还多
That's more than Santa Claus gets.
各自拥有卧室、电视和健身房
Each PreCog has their own bedroom, TV and weight room.
当先知真好
It's wonderful to be a PreCog.
我妈妈的新男朋友来访
My mom's new boyfriend came over again last night.
他脑袋不太灵光
He's just not very intelligent.
妈妈不让我在房间里吃饭 他逼我听她唠叨个没完
My mom wouldn't let me eat upstairs. I had to listen to him go on and on.
可恶，可恶
Shit!
眼珠扫瞄：约翰安德顿，允许进入
Eyedent: John Anderton. Approved for entry.
…我会养，因为我很会照顾你们
Which I told her I'd be able to do. I'm so good at taking care of you.
但她说我会不负责，乱讲
But she thinks I'll be irresponsible. It's ridiculous because...
不！你不能进来，你想干嘛？
You can't be in here. What are you doing here?
别跑，老头，谁让你进来？
Easy there, oldtimer. Who cleared you?
-你不能进来 -听我说，华利
You're not allowed here.  Listen, Wally.
-我认识你吗？ -我喜欢你
Do I know you?  I like you.
我不想动手动脚
So I don't wanna have to kick you or hit you.
只要你肯帮我
But only if you promise to help me.
嗨，约翰
Hi, John.
他像谁？
Who does that look like to you?
不知道
I don't know.
是亚嘉莎 他到这里来找她
It's Agatha. He's coming here to get her.
-这些是她的预视影像？ -我正在回转
Are these all of her previsions?  I'm rewinding her right now.
帮我找出里欧克罗的谋杀案
Just take me to the Leo Crow murder.
没有次序，按照她的原始输出
They don't come out in any order. I'm getting them as she's giving them.
看到了吗？
Can you see?
-他在里面 -他戴着面具之类的东西
He's inside.  He has some kind of mask on.
-门被他封住了 -糟了
He sealed the door.  Shit!
圣殿里不准用武器！ 用泡沫胶
Nobody fires a weapon inside the temple. Use bindfoam.
-有别的出口吗？ -所有门都守住了
Is there another way out of there?  All the doors are covered.
约翰，离开乳液槽！ 不要靠近乳液槽，约翰！
John, move away from the tank. Move away from the tank, John.
为什么要带走先知？
What does he want with a PreCog?
你说呢？ 他想杀谁就没人知道啦！
So he can kill whoever he wants to without anyone knowing.
但还有两位 华利！其它两位还有功能吧？
Well, there's still the other two. The other two can still function, right?
不！他们的心智共通 三个一起才有预测功能
They're a hive mind. It takes all three for their predictive abilities to work.
他们再也看不到凶杀案？
They can't see murders anymore?
失去一个男性可能还可以 但亚嘉莎是关键
Agatha, she's the key. She's the one they listen to...
她的能力最强，其它人都听她的
...the one with the most talent.
-她会照顾其它两位 -天啊
She takes care of the other two.  Jesus.
-把她找回来 -查出水管的流向
Please bring her back.  Every team underground, now!
-没有用的 -在蓄水池拦下他
It doesn't matter. He wins.  We'll stop him.
他杀克罗时她也在 她已经是他未来的一部分
She's with him when he kills Crow. She's already a part of his future.
杰德，想办法查出那个房间
Jad, put everything you've got into finding that room, and we stop a murder.
-还有多少时间？ -还有…
How much time have we got, Gordon?  We've got...
51分30秒
...51 minutes, 30 seconds.
你冷吗？ 你听得懂吗？
You cold? Can you understand me?
冷吗？ 你在颤抖是因为注射药剂
Are you cold? The shivers, it's the drugs we gave you.
很快就会消退了 对不起，我需要你帮忙
It should wear off soon. I'm sorry. I need your help.
你体内有我要的信息 我得知道怎么输出
You contain information. I need to know how to get at it.
可以告诉我谁是里欧克罗吗？
Can you just tell me who Leo Crow is?
-这是现在吗？ -什么？
Is it now?  What?
这是现在吗？
Is it now?
是的，眼前的事物就是现在
Yes, this is all happening right now.
我们会去到公共场所
I'm taking you some place in public...
这表示我得帮你找些别的衣服
...which means you need something else to wear.
我好累 我厌倦了未来
I'm tired. I'm tired of the future.
宅本先生！欢迎光临Gap服饰
Hello, Mr. Yakamoto, welcome back to the Gap.
上次买的无袖上衣喜欢吗？
How'd those assorted tank tops work out for you?
宅本先生？
Mr. Yakamoto?
鲍小姐，还需要另一对羚羊皮鞋吗？
Miss Belfor, did you come back for another pair of those chammy laceups?
-如果是绑架，怎么不开条件？ -不是绑架
If it's ransom, where's the damn note?  It has nothing to do with ransom.
他要亚嘉莎体内的信息
It has to do with the information inside of Agatha.
-他想证明自己是无辜的 -但下载需要技术支持
He's trying to prove his innocence.  He can't download her without support.
一般消费者买不到这种装备
Your average consumer can't buy any of this stuff.
它得用订制零件组合而成
It's been assembled and scrounged from spare parts made to order.
假如安德顿订制后 谁能帮他组合？
Assuming Anderton ordered this, who put it together?
鲁法斯莱理是什么人？
Who's Rufus T. Riley?
你喜欢哪种乐趣？我们全都有
What's your pleasure? We got it all here: Sports fantasies...
我们有运动幻觉、飞行幻觉…
..."Look, Ma, I can fly" fantasies...
从高空弹跳到翱翔大峡谷都有
...which covers everything from bungee jumping to flying over the Grand Canyon.
男人可以模拟女人的性经验
You can experience sex as a woman.
女人模拟跟偶像明星上床
Women come in to get laid by their favorite soap star.
这一种最安全卫生，有益健康
Or just some good, clean fun.
高潮迭起，但绝不得心脏病
It's a big rush, but you come out without a heart attack.
我想杀我老板
I wanna kill my boss.
没问题
Okay.
-能提供我几个影像吗？ -鲁法斯！
You got some images I can work with?  Rufus.
扮演费城爱乐指挥
Yeah, being concertmaster for the Philadelphia Symphony...
很受欢迎
...is a popular choice.
-不，我想杀我老板 -变态！
I wanna kill my boss.  You sick bastard.
你这种人唯恐天下不乱
You make this a terrible world to live in!
没想到全天下条子都在找你
Detective, nice of you to come here, seeing how every cop is looking for you.
-我需要你帮我 -来这干嘛？
I need your help.  Why'd you come here?
-我可以到府服务 -我要你帮我跟她
I make house calls.  I need your help with her.
哈，小甜心 不简单，一边逃亡
Hello, honey pie. I'm impressed. You're on the lam...
还有时间搞艳遇
...and you still have the time to slice off a little... jerky for yourself.
-她是先知 -靠，还是个先知
She's a PreCog.  Oh, yeah, okay.
-是啊 -她是先知
That's right.  She's a PreCog.
你把先知带来这里
You brought a PreCog here.
我的老天啊
Jesus Christ.
-你看到我心里想什么吗？ -起来
Are you reading my mind right now?  Get up.
将来的事我很抱歉 过去的事不是我干的
I'm sorry for whatever I'm gonna do. I swear I didn't do that stuff I did.
她体内有信息，我要下载出来
She has information inside her. I need you to get it out.
不行，连怎么下手我都不知道
No way. I wouldn't even know where to begin.
对艾莲娜表妹纯粹只是幻想
Those thoughts about my cousin were just thoughts.
-你因为严重黑客行为被捕两次 -又怎样？
You've been busted for felony hacking.  So?
用黑客技术侵入她
So I need you to hack into her.
这样好了，我帮你 但取得的影像我要保留
I do this, I get to keep whatever images I get from her head.
-任何人都不该私自拥有 -带她去光华商场
They don't belong to anybody.  Take her to RadioShack.
你一定得帮我
You're gonna help me.
亚嘉莎，我想看我的未来
Agatha, I need to see. I need to see what's gonna happen to me.
事成之后就离开
And then we'll go.
-她真的行的通 -慢一点
She works.  Slow it down.
怎么弄？打她的头不成？
How do I slow this down? I should hit her on the head?
-有录下来吗？ -妈的
Are you recording this?  Shit.
正在录
Yeah, recording.
这里我看过，往前
I know this already. Come on. Move on.
再见，克罗
Goodbye, Crow.
-怎么了？ -不知道
What happened?  I don't know.
-怎么了？ -不知道…
What happened?  I don't...
-怎么回事？其它影像呢？ -可能只有这些
Where's the rest of it?  I guess that's all of it.
我的关键报告呢？
Where's my Minority Report?
到底存不存在？
Do I even have one?
-到底有没有？ -没有
Do I have one?  No.
-什么？ -没有
What?  No.
怎么了？
What?
亚嘉莎？怎么了？ 怎么了？
Agatha? What? What?
-看到了吗？ -看什么？
Can you see?  See what?
安莉芙丽
Anne Lively.
你要我看谁杀了她 有录下来吗？
You want me to see who killed Anne Lively. Are you recording this?
有，可是，是倒转的
Yeah, but it's pouring out of her backwards.
我喜欢我的生活，一切都美好
I like my life. Everything's good.
他们进来了
They're inside.
谁？
Who?
你的老队友
All your old teammates.
肯尼，左边那间 艾伦，直走！
Kenny, left chamber. Alan, straight across.
没有！
Negative!
-没有！ -没有！
Negative!  Negative!
我不配
I don't deserve that.
-你最伟大 -不，你才伟大
You are the man.  No, you're the man.
看到雨伞没有？
Can you see the umbrella?
拿一把
Take it.
拿走！
Take it!
穿蓝色西装那个人 他的手提箱掉了
A man in a blue suit. He drops his briefcase.
美国新闻 谋杀案件逼近
穿棕色洋装的女人认出你的脸
You see a woman in a brown dress. She knows your face.
转弯
Turn in here.
走吧
Let's go.
-等等 -不能待在这里
Wait.  No, we can't stop here.
看到卖气球的人吗？
Can you see the balloon man?
等一下
Wait.
-等一下 -等什么？
Wait.  What are we waiting for?
等一下
Wait. Wait.
Wait.
-妈妈，我可以买个气球吗？ -好吧
Please, Mommy, can I have one?  All right.
等一下
Wait.
谢谢
Thank you.
-有谁发现他吗？ -没有
Anybody got an ID? Anybody?  Negative.
史考特和拉莫司搜东边 其它人跟我来
Scott, Ramos, take the east end. Everyone else, follow me. Let's go.
他知道了，不要回家
He knows. Don't go home.
发现他们了
We've got eyes on.
他们在工作，但他们站在…
They're working, but they're standing on it.
拜托，赏个零钱
Please! Please! Have you got a quarter?
丢些钱下去
Drop some money.
不能放在我手里吗？
Can't you put it in my hand?
上帝保佑你
May the Lord bless you.
感谢上帝
May God take care of you.
可恶！
Damn!
他就是那个人 窗外的那人
That's the guy. The man in the window.
-一晚95元 -可以看一下住客名单吗？
Rooms are 95 a night.  Mind if I look at the registry?
不行
I mind.
现在可以吗？
How about now?
请便
Help yourself.
克罗里
他在这儿
He's here.
安德顿，走吧
Anderton, leave.
你还有选择，立刻离开
You have a choice. Walk away. Do it now.
不行，我想知道我怎么了
I can't. I have to find out what happened in my life.
求求你
Please.
我不会杀他，我根本不认识他
Agatha, I'm not gonna kill the man. I don't even know him.
-克罗住哪一间？
What room is Crow in?  1006.
走吧
Come on.
走错房间
Wrong room.
你走
Leave.
快走啊
噢，天啊
Oh, God.
是西恩
This is Sean.
我儿子
My son.
过去六年的每一天 我只想着两件事：
Every day for the last six years I've thought about only two things:
第一是我儿子长大成人的模样
The first is what my son would look like if he were alive today...
在街上遇到，我认得出他吗？
...if I would recognize him if I saw him on the street.
第二是怎么对付绑走他的人？
And the second is what I would do to the man who took him.
你说对了
You're right.
没有人设计陷害我
I'm not being set up.
你得带我回家
You have to take me home.
你说过，没有关键报告
You said so yourself. There is no Minority Report.
未来是唯一的
I don't have an alternate future.
我一定会杀掉这个人
I am going to kill this man.
你还有选择 其它人没看过未来
You still have a choice. The others never saw their future.
你还有选择！
You still have a choice.
-里欧克罗？ -你是什么人？
Leo Crow?  Who the hell are you?
六年前在巴尔的摩，你在
Six years ago, Baltimore...
法兰西公共泳池绑走一个小孩
...you grabbed a kid at Francis public pool on the West End.
有吗？我一点都不记得
Did I? I don't remember anything about that place.
我是谁？我是谁？
Who am I? Who am I?
你知道我是谁吗？
Do you know who I am?
-你是某人的父亲 -他名叫西恩！
You're somebody's father.  His name is Sean!
西恩！
Sean!
我跟他说我是警察 我请他帮忙
I told him I was a policeman and needed his help.
我唱歌给他听 还买了个胡椒饼给他
It wasn't so bad. I sang him a song. I bought him a pretzel.
他很开心，他很开心
He was happy. He was happy.
他还活着吗？还活着吗？ 他在哪里？
Is he alive? He's alive. Where have you got him?
他好吗？ 他在哪，贱种？！
Is he all right? Tell me, you fuck, where is he?!
装在桶子里，沉进大海
I put him in a barrel. I sunk him in the bay.
它又浮上来 我抱他出来
He floated back up. I took him out.
我很温柔，我很温柔
I was gentle. I was gentle.
我对他很温柔
I was gentle.
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的很对不起
I'm so very sorry.
你怎么可以这样对待我儿子？
How could you do that to my...?
你可以选择
You can choose.
你还可以选择
警示
你有权保持沉默
You have the right to remain silent.
你所说的话可能成为不利证词
Anything you say or do can be used against you in a court of law.
你有权聘请辩护律师
You have the right to an attorney...
代为回答任何询问
...now and during any further questioning.
如果你请不起律师
If you can't afford an attorney...
我们将为你指派一位
...we will appoint one.
了解你的权利了吗？
Do you understand these rights?
你不杀我？
You're not gonna kill me?
-你了解你的权利了吗？ -你不杀我？
Do you understand these rights?  You're not gonna kill me?
不按照计划进行 我家人什么都得不到
If you don't go through with this, my family gets nothing.
你该杀我啊！ 他说你会的
You're supposed to kill me. He said you would.
他？他是谁？
He? Who's he?
我不知道 他打电话到监狱给我
I don't know. He called me in my cell.
他说我答应的话，我会获释 家人可以得到一笔钱
He told me I'd be released if I went along, and my family would be cared for.
答应做什么？
If you did what?
假装杀了你儿子，清楚吗？
If I acted like I killed your kid. Okay?
假装杀我儿子？
If you killed my kid?
你不杀我，我家人什么都没有
Look, you don't kill me, my family gets nothing. Okay?
照片哪里来的？
What about the pictures?
假的，他给我的
They're fake. He gave them to me.
听我说…
Now, listen to me. You...
跟我说是谁布的局？
You tell me: Who was it that set this up?
我不知道
I don't know.
-动手啊！ -我再问一次
Come on.  I'm asking you again:
-谁雇你的？ -我没看过他的脸
Who put you up to this?  I didn't see his face.
说出来，我家人什么都得不到
I tell you who, and my family gets nothing.
-跟我说 -杀了我
Who made you do this?  Kill me.
-动手杀了我 -说
You can do this. Kill me.  Tell me.
-杀我 -里欧，枪放开
Kill me.  Leo, let go of the gun.
枪放掉，不会有事
Let go of the gun. It's okay.
枪放掉，对 枪放掉
Let go of the gun. That's it. Let go of the gun.
你不杀我
You're not gonna kill me.
-再见，克罗 -安德顿，等等！
Goodbye, Crow.  Anderton, wait a sec...!
-你看到了吗？ -退后！
Did you see it?  Stay back!
发生什么事了？
What's happening down there?
谋杀！
Murder!
不合常理
Doesn't make sense.
如果你是杀小孩凶手 会随便展示照片？
If you were a child killer, would you leave these photos out?
或许是安德顿拿出来的
Anderton might have found them.
-你以前在哪里服务？ -财政部
What kind of cop were you before this?  Treasury agent.
你第一次到凶案现场？ 我以前在重案组
This will be your first murder scene? I worked homicide before federal.
这正是所谓的“过度证据”
This is an orgy of evidence.
-猜猜我遇过几次过度证据的案子？ -几次？
Know how many orgies I had as a cop?  How many?
一次也没有
None.
这全是安排好的
This was all arranged.
今天发生了犯罪预防中心 开始六年后的首桩凶杀案
Today we saw the first murder in the six years of the Precrime experiment.
不幸，悲剧是因为人为疏失
Sadly enough, this failure was human.
保护小组未能及时拦阻
The protection team simply didn't get there in time.
但凶案本身 跟先知预测的完全吻合
But the murder itself happened exactly as the PreCogs predicted it would.
我们可以掀开一些 预犯系统的神秘面纱
Today's event put a human face on the Precrime system.
丹尼威妥来电 他说极为重要
Danny Witwer's on the phone. He says it's important.
拉玛？
Lamar?
-什么事？ -出问题了
What?  There's something wrong.
我们追错对象 电话不方便说
We're chasing the wrong man. I don 't wanna say over the phone.
安德顿家见
Meet me at Anderton 's.
从克罗的饭店房间找到的
We recovered that from Leo Crow's hotel room.
记得在巴尔的摩 我亲手交给他这个
I remember when I gave this to him, back in Baltimore.
请坐，先生
Please, sir.
你找到些什么？
Tell me what you have.
这是安莉芙丽的谋杀案
This is the murder of a woman named Anne Lively.
约翰跟我说过 从看守所拿到的？
John told me about this. You got this from Containment?
对，是阿瑟和戴希尔的
Yes. This is from the twins, Arthur and Dashiell.
亚嘉莎的失踪了
Agatha's stream was missing.
这份来自“虚拟实境”
This one is from the Cyber Parlor.
安德顿从亚嘉莎身上载下来 鲁法斯莱理录下来的
Anderton downloaded this directly from Agatha. Rufus Riley recorded it.
-同样的预视影像 -不完全相同
It's the same prevision.  Not quite.
你看水面的风，注意涟漪
Look at the surface wind across the water. Watch the ripples.
从岸边向外波动
Moving away from shore.
第二份取自看守所的影像 阿瑟和戴希看到的
Now the second image, the one from Containment that Art and Dash saw.
注意看水
Watch the water.
风向变了 涟漪的波动方向相反
The wind's changed. The ripples are moving the other way.
凶案在不同的时间发生
This murder's taking place at two different times.
所长说 安德顿被通缉前看过这影像
Anderton was watching this right before he was tagged.
他跟我说过失踪的资料
He told me about the missing data stream.
-他怕落到你手中 -对，我找到了
He was concerned you might find it.  He was right. I did.
影像一直在亚嘉莎体内
It was inside of Agatha.
为什么有人想删除档案？
So the question is, why would someone want this erased from the data file?
丹尼，直接告诉我你怎么想
Danny, just tell me what you're thinking.
我认为有个凶手逍遥法外
I'm thinking someone got away with murder.
怎么可能？
How?
杰德说先知会 重复看见同一凶案
Jad told me that sometimes the PreCogs see the same murder more than once.
-那称为回音 -杰德称之为前视印象
It's called an echo.  Jad called it PreCog deja vu.
我们要求技术人员将它剔除
We teach the techs to identify and disregard them.
没错，但是 如果技术人员误认是回音呢？
Yeah, but what if a technician only thought he was looking at an echo?
假如是另一桩凶案呢？
What if he was looking at a completely different murder altogether?
我不懂
I don't understand.
凶手只要雇人去杀安莉芙丽
All you'd have to do is hire someone to kill Anne Lively...
例如有毒瘾的流浪汉，一无所有
...like a drifter, a neuroin addict, someone with nothing to lose.
防罪中心一开始拦阻了凶案
Precrime stops the murder from taking place...
凶手戴了头铐，入了狱 但紧跟着，另外有人…
...haloes the killer, takes him away. But then, right then, someone else...
看过影像，装扮成凶手…
...having reviewed the prevision and dressed in the same clothes...
以同样手法执行谋杀
...commits the murder in exactly the same way.
技术人员以为是回音，删除掉
Technician takes a look, thinks he's looking at an echo, erases it.
一定是有权看影像的人
It'd have to be someone with access to the previsions in the first place.
某位高层人士
Someone fairly highup.
你听见我听到什么吗？
Do you know what I hear?
什么也没有 天花板没脚步声
Nothing. No footsteps up the stairs.
窗外没飞行器 没有蜘蛛的沙沙声
No hovercraft out the window. No clicketyclick of little spyders.
为什么听不到？
Do you know why?
先知看不到任何东西
Because right now, the PreCogs can't see a thing.
看到没？好美啊
Can you see? It's beautiful.
-我们要去哪里？ -安全的地方
Where are we going?  Someplace safe.
-我是伯吉斯 -拉玛，我是劳拉
Burgess.  Lamar, it's Lara.
-是的，劳拉 -请你一定要帮他
Yes, Lara.  You have to help him.
他在那里吗？
Is he there?
先知跟他在一起吗？
Is the PreCog with him?
留住他们，我马上过来
Keep them there. I'm on my way.
别告诉丹尼威妥，我信不过他
Please don't tell Danny Witwer. I don't trust him.
我绝口不提
I won't say a word.
不要让约翰离开，好吗？
You just don't let John leave, all right?
他不是凶手，拉玛
He's no killer, Lamar.
我知道
I know.
好冷
It's cold.
劳拉，她是亚嘉莎
Lara, this is Agatha.
记得我为你和西恩 念“汤姆历险记”吗？
You remember when I would read Tom Sawyer to you and Sean?
汤姆和贝齐在山洞失踪时 他好害怕
He got so scared when Tom and Becky were lost in the cave.
我想坐下来
I gotta sit down.
好好想清楚
I gotta figure this out.
一定得想出来
他们利用西恩
They used Sean.
让我误以为克罗杀了西恩
They wanted me to think Crow killed him.
但他没有
But he didn't.
他没有
He didn't.
他们为什么要陷害你？
Why would they set you up?
因为我发现她的事
Because I found out about her.
谁的事？
About who?
-我以前怎么没发现？ -发现什么？
How could I not have seen this?  Seen what?
安莉芙丽
Anne Lively.
亚嘉莎？
Agatha.
海曼博士说过“逝者未逝
Dr. Hineman once said, "The dead don't die...
他们依旧守护我们”
...they look on and help. "
记得吗，约翰？
Remember that, John.
亚嘉莎
Agatha.
西恩
Sean.
他正在沙滩上
He's on the beach now...
脚趾泡着海水
...toe in the water.
他要你一起陪他
He's asking you to come in with him.
他在沙滩上跟妈妈赛跑
He's been racing his mother up and down the sand.
这个家有好多爱
There's so much love in this house.
他已经十岁了
He's 10 years old.
被一群动物围绕着
He's surrounded by animals.
他想当兽医
He wants to be a vet.
你们让他养兔子、小鸟和狐狸
You keep a rabbit for him, a bird and a fox.
他念中学了
He's in high school.
他跟爸爸一样爱跑步
He likes to run, like his father.
他参加两里长跑和接力赛
He runs the twomile and the long relay.
他23岁了
He's 23.
他在念大学
He's at a university.
他跟美丽的克蕾儿做爱
He makes love to a pretty girl named Claire.
他向她求婚
He asks her to be his wife.
他打电话告诉哭泣的劳拉
He calls here and tells Lara, who cries.
他继续跑步
He still runs...
约翰看着他跑在校园和体育馆
...across the university and in the stadium, where John watches.
他跑得跟他爸爸一样快
Oh, God. He's running so fast, just like his daddy.
他看见爸爸，他想跑向他
He sees his daddy. He wants to run to him.
但他只有六岁 他办不到
But he's only 6 years old, and he can't do it.
而且那个人太快了
And the other man is so fast.
这个家有好多爱
There was so much love in this house.
我好想要他回来
I want him back so bad.
她也一样
So did she.
你没看到吗？
Can't you see?
她希望她女儿回来
She just wanted her little girl back.
但来不及了
But it was too late.
她女儿走了
Her little girl was already gone.
她还活着
She's still alive.
她没死
She didn't die.
但她也不算活着
But she's not alive.
亚嘉莎？
Agatha?
跟我说
Just tell me...
谁杀了你母亲？
...who killed your mother?
谁杀了安莉芙丽？
Who killed Anne Lively?
对不起，约翰 你又得逃了
I'm sorry, John, but you're gonna have to run again.
-什么？ -快逃！
What?  Run!
我爱你
I love you.
-不会有事的 -跟他去，不会有事
It's okay.  You'll be fine with them.
-不！不！ -跟着我
No! No!  Stay with me. Stay with me.
-约翰，不 -不要说话
John, no.  Don't talk.
约翰安德顿
John Anderton.
根据特区犯罪预防中心的授权
By mandate of the D.C. Precrime Division...
你因为谋害克罗和威妥被捕
...I'm placing you under arrest for the murders of Leo Crow and Danny Witwer.
好了
That's it.
好乖
That's my girl.
我担心死了
I was so worried about you.
他有伤害你吗？
Did he hurt you?
我好想你
I missed you so much.
没关系了，有华利在
It's okay. Wally's here.
有华利在
Wally's here.
成了我的阶下囚了，约翰
You're a part of my flock now, John.
欢迎
Welcome.
里面其实挺舒服的 据说你会看到影像
It's actually kind of a rush. They say you have visions...
你的一辈子不停在眼前播放
...that your life flashes before your eyes...
你的梦想都会成真
...that all your dreams come true.
（约翰安德顿）
都是我的错
This is all my fault.
谁也改变不了这个事实
There was nothing anyone could do.
我猜你想拿回他的东西吧
I thought you might want to have those.
多年没穿，希望今晚能穿
I haven't worn this in years. I wanted to make sure it fits before tonight.
很好看
You look great.
我知道他有很多麻烦 但我却未伸出援手
I knew he was having trouble for some time, yet I did nothing.
-“今日美国”记者来了 -现在不行
The guy from USA Today is here.  Tell him not now.
-他只想… -没空！
He just wanted a few minutes before...  Not now!
-我以为你想退休了 -想过
I thought you were retiring.  Well, I was.
约翰的事让我感到系统的脆弱
But this incident with John made me realize the fragility of all this.
这里是约翰也是我的毕生结晶
This is John's legacy as much as it is my own.
我有义务保护它
Now I have an obligation to protect that.
我知道你难以接受
Lara, I know how difficult this is for you.
但，或许你可以放下心中的石头
But maybe you can find some closure in the fact...
约翰终于找出杀你儿子的凶手
...that John finally found the man who killed your son.
谁是安莉芙丽？
Who's Anne Lively?
-谁？ -安莉芙丽
Who?  Anne Lively.
他被捕前正谈到她
John was talking about her right before they took him.
我不知道她是谁
I don't know who that is.
他说他因为发现她所以被陷害
John said something about him being set up because he found out about her.
-但我们知道约翰为什么被通缉 -他还说克罗是个幌子
Well, we know why John was tagged.  He also said Crow was a fake.
威妥呢？他在约翰家中 被约翰的枪所杀
And Witwer? He was killed with John's gun inside John's apartment.
知道约翰来此工作的原因吗？
Do you know the reason why John came here to work for you?
-为了西恩？ -对
Sean.  Yes.
他到此工作，因为他以为
He came here to work for you because he thought...
防止类似的事情再发生
...if he could just stop that kind of thing from happening...
-我了解 -不，你不了解
I understand.  No, I don't think you do.
先生，他们两分钟后 要举行记者会
Sir, they wanna start the press conference in two minutes.
劳拉
Lara...
约翰是最顶尖的警察
...John was the best cop I ever knew...
某方面说，更是个好人
...and, in some ways, also the best man.
但每天带着那份伤痛
But the scars he carried around...
他会希望我们记得他好的一面
Well, I know he'd want us to honor the good things we remember about him.
我也知道他为什么跟你结婚 你跟他一样固执
And I also know why he married you: You're as stubborn as he is.
-拉玛 -你会打领带吧？
Lamar...  Do you know how to tie one of these?
可以帮个忙吗？我笨手笨脚
Could you please give me a hand? I'm all thumbs, as you see.
我会这么办
Listen, I'll tell you what I'll do.
到周一，我首先会调阅威妥的证物
First thing Monday, I'll look over the Witwer evidence.
我会请吉狄恩查看守所档案
And I'll have Gideon run the Containment files...
看有没有溺毙女性叫…
...see if anyone drowned a woman by the name of...
你说她叫什么名字？
What did you say her name was?
安莉芙丽
Anne Lively.
但我没说过她是溺毙的
But I never said she drowned.
-先生，记者会开始了 -我马上过去
Sir, the press conference is starting.  I'll be right there.
我们稍后再谈
We'll talk about this later.
明天或许到小屋拜访你
Perhaps tomorrow, I'll come by the cottage.
我想跟我先生说句话
I'd like a word with my husband.
你没有授权
You're not authorized.
你怎么进来的？
How did you get in here?
谢谢
Thank you.
各位女士先生，拉玛伯吉斯 新成立的国家预测犯罪局长
Ladies and gentlemen, Lamar Burgess, director of the new National Precrime.
我代表全体员工献给您
On behalf of your staff, we present you with this.
-恭喜 -哇！
Congratulations, sir.  My God.
你们怎么负担得起？
How did you get this?
我扣了你六个月特支费
I padded your expense account for six months.
这款左轮枪 是由士兵献给将军们的
Revolvers like this one were given to generals...
以纪念南北战争结束
...at the end of the Civil War by their troops.
枪膛内装填了 五发镀金子弹
The cylinders were loaded with five goldplated bullets...
五发镀金子弹，象征…
...to symbolize the end of the destruction and death...
终结撕裂国家的破坏与死亡
...that had ripped the country apart for five years.
防罪中心提升为国家机构后
Ladies and gentlemen, with Precrime going national...
或许可以期待一个时代的来临
...maybe we can all look forward to a time when none of us...
再也毋需发射任何一颗子弹
...will have to discharge another firearm ever again.
开始尽情享用！ 这是命令！
Now enjoy yourselves. Enjoy yourselves! That's an order.
周末可以常造访湖滨小屋了吧？
Does this mean we can finally use the lake house on weekends?
喂
Hello.
是的，马上
Yes. Right away.
-对不起，很抱歉 -对不起
Excuse me, so sorry.  Excuse me.
-局长？ -是的
Sir?  Yes.
你私人专线上有急电
Sir, you have an emergency call on your private line.
伯吉斯
Yes, this is Burgess.
哈，拉玛，恭喜 你成功了
Hello, Lamar. I just wanted to congratulate you. You did it.
你创造了一个没有凶杀案的世界
You created a world without murder.
大家想请你在帽子上签名，可以吗？
Everyone wants your name on a hat. Can you sign these?
你只要踩着别人的尸体往前走
All you had to do was kill someone to do it.
分析室，杰德
Aroom. Jad.
杰德，是劳拉，约翰请你帮个忙
Jad, it's Lara. John needs a favor.
-什么意思？ -亚嘉莎的母亲，安莉芙丽
What are you talking about?  Agatha 's mother, Anne Lively.
一位放弃孩子的死毒鬼
Just a junkie who had a kid once and had to give her up, but surprise!
没想到她戒了毒 想接女儿回家
She cleaned herself up, and she wanted her daughter back.
她想要回亚嘉莎
She wanted Agatha.
杰德，你看，只有亚嘉莎的影像 没有时间也没有附属数据
Jad, you getting this? It's from the female only. No time or incident data.
这不是未来，已经发生过了
It isn't the future. It already happened.
问题是，没有亚嘉莎 就没有防罪中心
And the problem was, without Agatha, there was no Precrime.
她一直是三位中最强的一位 没有亚嘉莎一切将化为乌有
She's the strongest of the three. Without Agatha, you had nothing.
没有她，你怎么可能 站在那里为大家签名
You wouldn't be where you are now, standing there, signing autographs.
-杰德，你在干嘛？ -你在干嘛？
What are you doing?  What are you doing with that?
-你想干嘛，大个子？ -传送前先想清楚
What you up to, big man?  Think before you send that.
慢一点
Slow down.
所以你不得不除掉安莉芙丽 真是项大工程
Now you had to get rid of Anne Lively, which presented a problem:
你怎么杀她又不被先知看见？
How can you kill her without the PreCogs seeing it?
很简单，利用你控制的系统
Simple. Use a system you control against her.
你雇杀手杀她 你知道先知会看见
You hired someone to kill her, knowing the PreCogs would see that murder.
你引诱安莉芙丽到湖边
You lured Anne Lively out to the lake...
承诺让她母女团圆
...with the promise of reuniting her with her daughter.
我女儿呢？
Where's my daughter?
哪里？
Where?
看！
Run!
快逃！
四下无人时，你亲手杀了她
When you were all alone, you killed her yourself...
使用与凶手同样的手法
...in the same way the PreCogs predicted your John Doe would kill her.
让实际谋杀看起来像回音
You made the real murder look like an echo...
而技术人员做了他们该做的： 不理会它
...knowing the tech would do what he was trained to do: Disregard it.
安莉芙丽变成另一个失踪人口
Anne Lively became just another missing person.
你现在怎么办，拉玛？
So, what are you gonna do, Lamar?
你要怎么办？
What are you gonna do?
红球状况！
We got a Red Ball!
（被害人 约翰安德顿）
想想小女孩救过的生命
Think about the lives that little girl has saved.
想想其它可以被拯救的生命
那小女孩可以救西恩
Think of all the lives she will save. She could have saved Sean.
不准你说他的名字！
Don't you ever say his name!
你利用我对亡儿的思念陷害我
You used the memory of my dead son to set me up.
你知道我会为他杀人
You knew that would drive me to murder.
-你现在怎么办，拉玛？ -你现在怎么办，拉玛？
What are you gonna do now, Lamar?  What are you gonna do now, Lamar?
-你要怎么 -封住我的嘴？
How are you gonna...?  Shut me up?
原谅我，约翰
Forgive me, John.
（凶手 拉玛伯吉斯）
拉玛
Lamar.
结束了
It's over.
剩下的唯一问题是，你怎么收场？
The question you have to ask is, what are you gonna do now?
毫无怀疑，先知已看见此事
No doubt the PreCogs have already seen this.
没错
No doubt.
你了解两难之处了吧？
You see the dilemma, don't you?
不杀我，表示先知错了 犯罪防治中心跟着完蛋
If you don't kill me, PreCogs were wrong and Precrime is over.
杀我，你前途就毁了
If you do kill me, you go away...
但证明系统有效，先知正确
...but it proves the system works. PreCogs were right.
所以，你该怎么办？
So, what are you gonna do now?
代价是什么？
What's it worth?
只不过是另一桩谋杀
Just one more murder.
你戴着头铐在地狱腐烂 但民众还是相信防罪中心
You'll rot in hell with a halo, but people will still believe in Precrime.
你只需杀了我，就像先知预测的
All you have to do is kill me, like they said you would.
除非
Except...
你知道自己的未来
...you know your own future...
也就是你能任意改变未来
...which means you can change it if you want to.
你还有选择，拉玛
You still have a choice, Lamar.
跟我一样
Like I did.
没错，我还有选择
Yes, I have a choice...
而且已经选好了
...and I made it.
原谅我，约翰
Forgive me, John.
原谅我
Forgive me.
原谅我，孩子
Forgive me, my boy.
拉玛！
Lamar!
2054年，实验六年之后 预测犯罪计划终遭放弃
In 2054, the sixyear Precrime experiment was abandoned.
所有囚犯无条件无罪释放
All prisoners were unconditionally pardoned and released...
虽然几位仍被警方追踪数年
...although police departments kept watch on many of them for years.
亚嘉莎与双胞胎
Agatha and the twins...
被移至一隐密场所
...were transferred to an undisclosed location...
一个他们能发挥天赋的地方
...a place where they could find relief from their gifts...
得以平静的安度余生
...a place where they could live out their lives in peace.
谢谢观赏
纪念麦克马西亚